# Jordan Wilson

Phone: (919) - 510 - 3202 | Email: Jordan Fitzgerald12@outlook.com Address: Haw River, NC 27258

#### PROFILE SUMMARY

Strategic, visionary, and solution-oriented IT Operations Manager with over 10 years of experience in providing IT support roadmaps for clients. Well-versed in monitoring daily computer operating systems and implementing process improvements that will enhance the quality of service. Demonstrated proficiency in handling various computer systems and applications and comfortable working in a team and self-directed settings. Adept at resolving complex technical issues and performing troubleshooting to identify the causes of problems and take appropriate measures to prevent a recurrence. Endowed with impeccable communication and interpersonal skills to build sustainable relationships with team members and stakeholders.

#### RELEVANT SKILLS HIGHLIGHT

- Technical troubleshooting
- Data management
- Application support
- Systems administration
- Team leadership

- Resources allocation
- Mobile device management
- Effective communication skills
- Installation procedures development
- Network administration

- Problem & conflict resolution
- Hardware & software analysis
- Report writing & documentation
- **Ouality** assurance
- Cross-functional collaboration

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Installing and implementing new programs, modules, servers, and hardware network equipment when necessary to upgrade and improve resources or increase compatibility.
- Overseeing deployment and maintenance processes for all implemented hardware, software, and operating systems.
- Performing technical troubleshooting to identify root causes of the problems and implement preventative measures to curb future recurrence.
- Providing technical support to end-users by analyzing system requirements to resolve various technical issues.
- Researching software and systems products to justify technical recommendations and support purchasing efforts.
- Working closely with technical teams to ensure that requirements are accurately translated into solutions.

#### PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

# Assistant IT Operations Manager | North Carolina Specialty Hospital - Durham, NC Responsibilities:

Feb 2022 - Present

- Provided Tier II level support for networking issues.
- Developed innovative procedures to reduce operational costs by 30% and improve performance levels by 50%.
- Assisted in the evaluation, recommended negotiations and contracts for the purchases of systems and software products
- Improved and standardized IT support processes leveraging capabilities of the specialty hospital staff and external partners.
- Ensure effective utilization of IT resources, including staff and equipment across various departments of the hospital.
- Analyzed and executed VMware performance tuning strategies
- Maintained, upgraded, and implemented improvements to the VMWare ESXi infrastructure

# IT Associate | Kennan Institute of Private Enterprise - Chapel Hill, NC

July 2019 - Feb 2022

- Responsibilities:
- Collaborated with and helped senior web developers to design, code, and maintain 20+ websites.
- Coordinated purchase, installation, and configuration of new software applications and computer hardware.
- Facilitated communications among different IT teams to meet and continuously improve the service level and quality.
- Provided adequate support to other IT personnel and made recommendations to improve IT and administrative processes.

# Worked cohesively with over 30 technical team members to research, troubleshoot and provide necessary solutions to network, hardware, and software-related issues and ensure 100% functionality.

## Help Desk Technician | DTiQ - Las Vegas, NV Responsibilities:

Feb 2018 - July 2019

- Oversaw and monitored infrastructure's performance to ensure everything runs 100% smoothly and securely.
- Replaced and upgraded defective or outdated system components to increase productivity and efficiency by 70%.
- Troubleshoot technical issues and ensure all systems were secured and protected from breach or virus risk.
- Assisted with migrating over 400 users from Google Suite to Microsoft Office 365.
- Devised strategic initiatives to install, configure and maintain 30+ networking infrastructures of the company.
- Managed and oversaw computers, users, and group accounts in an Active Directory environment.
- Utilized troubleshooting, logical processing and problem-solving skills to rectify hardware, software, and network issues.

### Junior Application Analyst | VCU Health Systems - Richmond, VA Responsibilities:

Nov 2015 - Sept 2017

Trained and mentored new residents and staff and developed procedures and documentation for user access.

- Provided strategic application support for maintaining daily operations to end users.
- Identified methodologies to streamline IT processes and improve the quality of customer services.
- Collaborated with other members to perform software testing and implementation and systems upgrades.
- Assisted with HL7 integration, planning and implementation of system changes.
- Administered access to the EMR system Patient Keeper and Cerner.

# Intern | VCU Health Systems - Richmond, VA

May 2011 - Aug 2014

#### Responsibilities:

- Worked directly with the helpdesk technicians to provide solutions to 80% of complex problems.
- Performed basic IT tasks such as setting up computers, responding to service desk tickets and troubleshooting issues.
- Recalled for three summers as a selected student intern in their Clinical Applications and mobility department
- Handled and managed all VCU's mobile device and EMR user account.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Nucamp Coding Bootcamp, Raleigh, NC

• Back End, SQL, and DevOps with Python

2022

### Radford University, Radford VA

Completed course work towards Bachelor of Science degree in Information Systems

2011-2016

#### CERTIFICATIONS

#### **Amazon Web Services**

Certified AWS Cloud Practitioner

Feb 2020 - Feb 2024

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- AWS/Azure/GCP
- PostgreSQL
- Office 365
- API and web services
- DevOps Frameworks
- Bash Scripting

- Active Directory
- Windows Server
- Group Policy
- HTML, CSS
- VMWare
- vivivvare
- TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP, VLANs
- Agile Software Development
- Jira
- SolarWinds
- ServiceNow
- Python
- Linux

#### ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS

- Ability to demonstrate flexibility in a dynamic, fast-paced, and challenging work environment.
- Fantastic ability to work collaboratively with technical team to provide scalable solutions.
- Outstanding communication skills (written and verbal) to communicate effectively.
- Great attention to detail and incredible ability to establish facts, define problems and provide solutions.
- Sound analytical skills, organizational and problem, and conflict resolution skills.

#### HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- Traveling
- Learning new things

- Reading
- Coding

#### REFERENCES

Available upon request